Guide to the Coolidge Family Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Coolidge Family papers
Undated
SC0471
Coolidge family.
2.75 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Dave Coolidge, 1993
Information about Access
None.
Biographical Note
The Coolidge family papers were largely generated by five sisters: Agnes Elizabeth Brown, Zaidee Brown, Harriett Brown Coolidge, Ellen Coit Brown Elliott, and Louise Brown Nash; their brother Bolton Coit Brown is also represented in the papers. They were the children of Martha Coit Brown and the Rev. Edmund Woodward Brown of Burdett, New York.
The family's affiliation with Stanford University began in 1891 with the appointment of Orrin Leslie Elliott, Ellen Brown's husband, as Secretary and Registrar, and Bolton C. Brown's appointment as art professor. Louise Brown moved out to assist her sister Ellen at home during that first year; she later married Herbert Nash, Stanford's first librarian. She was the artist for the Hopkins Seaside Laboratory from 1893 to 1897 and did scientific illustrations for many faculty members.
Zaidee Brown was a member of the Stanford class of 1898, earning a degree in English. She was a professional librarian, serving in various positions around the country. Harriett Brown earned her bachelor's degree in English at Stanford in May of 1902; she married Herbert Coolidge, a Stanford student during the years 1899 to 1904, in 1904. She was for many years a leader and teacher at the Santa Barbara Truth Center. Agnes E. Brown, also known as Bessie, earned her bachelor's degree in English at Stanford in May of 1906. She was also a librarian.
Scope and Contents Note
The Coolidge family papers consist of correspondence, journals, writings, genealogy, art work, and photographs of the Brown and Coolidge families. In addition to family letters and photographs, the collection includes the religious writings and radio talks of Harriett Brown Coolidge, 1936-1944; and scientific illustrations and art work of Louise Nash and her "journal letters" written during sketching trips, 1920s and 1930s. Of note among the family papers is the Brown family "newspaper," titled "Our Talk" or "Brown's Household Bulletin." They include sketches by Bolton C. Brown and Lousie Brown and Ellen Brown's account of a reception for University President Andrew White at Cornell (1882). The photograph album includes images of Harriett Brown Coolidge and her children Ruth and Coit, Agnes E. Brown, Mary Roberts Smith who married Dane Coolidge, Zaidee Brown and other librarians at Washington State College and at Long Beach public library, the Santa Barbara Truth Center, and several images of Stanford University taken by Ellen Coit Elliott.
Access Terms
Brown family.; Brown, Agnes Elizabeth.; Brown, Bolton, 1864-1936.; Brown, Edmund Woodward.; Brown, Zaidee M., (Zaidee Mabel), 1875-1950.; Coolidge, Harriett Brown.; Coolidge, Mary Roberts,, 1860-1945.; Cornell University. -- General subdivision--Presidents.;; Elliott, Ellen Coit.; Nash, Louise Brown.; Santa Barbara Truth Center..; Stanford University -- Form subdivision--Photographs.;; White, Andrew Dickson,, 1832-1918.; Artists.; Families--History.--California; Families--History.--New York (State); Illustrations.; Journals.; Librarians.; Photoprints.; Religious broadcasting--California.; Sermons.
Collection Contents
- Brown, Agnes. Letters from the Parker family, 1927-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Brown, Agnes. Letters from nieces and nephews (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Brown, Agnes. Letters from Gertrude Brown and Zaidee Brown (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Brown, Agnes. Letters to family, 1889-1899 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Brown, Agnes. Journal, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Brown, Agnes. Sketches (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Brown, Agnes. Scrapbook of published work, 1920-1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brown, Agnes. Scrapbook covers (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brown, Bolton. The Painter's Palette and How to Master It. (two copies) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Brown, Bolton. Publications by or about (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Brown, Edmund W. Letters written from Palo Alto and Stanford, 1896-1899 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Brown, Edmund W. Biographical notes on, by Ellen Coit Elliott (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Brown, Zaidee. Letters out, 1889-1891 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Brown, Zaidee. Letters out, 1892-1893 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Brown, Zaidee. Letters out, 1894-1897 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Brown, Zaidee. Letters out, 1901-1902 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Brown, Zaidee. Letters out, May 19, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Brown, Zaidee. Letter fragments (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Brown, Zaidee. Personal letters received, 1895-1902 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Brown, Zaidee. Letters and papers re her library work, 1908-1933 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Brown, Zaidee. Letters received at leaving Montclair College, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Brown, Zaidee. Published works (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Brown Family. "Our Talk," January 1879 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Brown Family. "Our Talk," February 1879 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Brown Family. "Brown's Household Bulletin," June 18, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Brown Family. "Our Talk," 1882 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Brown Family. Miscellaneous items (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Pressed flower book (Herbarium and Plant Descriptions) with specimens from Burdett and Watkins, NY, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Autobiography (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Bible interpretation, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Certificate of cremation, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Letters to family, 1904, 1919, and undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Letters out, 1944 (copies) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Letters from her son Coit, 1910, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Letters from her mother, 1914-1915 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Meditations, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Miscellaneous religious writings (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Poetry (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Printed writings (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, 1936-37 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, 1939-40 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, 1940 (notes for talks) (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, 1941 schedule (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, January 11, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, March 2, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, March 16, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, March 23, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, March 30, 1941 (Folder 20)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, April 28, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, May 6, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, May 13, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, May 20, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, May 27, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, June 3, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, June 6, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, June 17, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, June 24, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, July 1, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, July 8, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, July 15, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, July 22, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, July 29, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, August 5, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, August 12, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, August 19, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, August 26, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, September 2, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, September 8/9, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, September 16, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, September 23, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, September 30, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, September 1941 (5 talks) (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, October 7, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, October 14, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, October 21, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, October 28, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, January 1943 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, February 1943 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, March 1943 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, May-September 1943 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Radio talks, fragments (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. "Things to Be Remembered," 1939 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. "Truth Primer of Young People" (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Copy of Scribblers inscribed to HBC, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Letters of sympathy on her death, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Sympathy cards on her death, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Coolidge, Harriett Brown. Typescript of "A Woman's Experience in a Railroad Outfit," as told by Mrs. Tom Andrews (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Coolidge, Ruth. Miscellaneous papers (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Coolidge Family. Miscellaneous items (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Elliott, Ellen C. Letters written during European trips, 1922, 1925, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Elliott, Ellen C. Letter about her mother's last days, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Elliott, Ellen C. Poem in The Lyric West, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Nash, Louise. Art work (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Nash, Louise. Art work (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Nash, Louise. Clippings (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Nash, Louise. Drawings of fish and skulls (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Nash, Louise. Drawings, scientific, published (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Nash, Louise. Drawings, scientific, scrapbook (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Nash, Louise. Exhibition at Stanford Art Gallery (description) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Nash, Louise. Journal, 1877 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Nash, Louise. Journal, 1906-1943 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Nash, Louise. Journal letter, February-March, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Nash, Louise. Journal letter, Massachusetts, July, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Nash, Louise. Journal letter, New Hampshire, no date (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Nash, Louise. Journal letter, Palm Springs and Colorado, no date (missing pages) (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Nash, Louise. Journal letter, fragments (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Nash, Louise. Letters to Bess, 1934-1945 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Nash, Louise. Letters to family, 1886, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Nash, Louise. Letters to Christian Science Monitor (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Nash, Louise. Letter fragments (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Nash, Louise. Letter received (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Nash, Louise. Memories of sketching trips (damaged) (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Nash, Louise. Notebook "About Morning" compiled by Bess for Louise, July, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Nash, Louise. Professional papers (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Genealogy. Caulkins colonial family (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Genealogy. Coit family (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Genealogy. Copies of family documents (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Genealogy. Miscellaneous items (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Genealogy. North family (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Genealogy. Notes from E.F. Brown's research (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Genealogy. Woodward line (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Genealogy. Woodward line (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous publications (Box 6, Folder NF)
- Photographs. Album (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Photographs. Agnes E. Brown (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Photographs. Agnes E. Brown and Charles Story at Monterey, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Photographs. Elizabeth Coit Brown; Mary R. Brown (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Photographs. Mildred Brown (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Photographs. Brown sisters as young women (Elizabeth, Agnes, Harriett, Gertrude) (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Photographs. Harriett B. Coolidge (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Photographs. Postcards (mostly of Susanville, CA, and Watkins Glen, NY) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Photographs. Stanford University arboretum, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Photographs. Unidentified tintype and miscellaneous photographs (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Nash, Louise. Art work (Box OS env)